The greatest love story ever told.
Cinderella is a family, fantasy, animation film directed by Clyde Geronimi.
Cinderella has faith her dreams of a better life will come true.
With help from her loyal mice friends and a wave of her Fairy Godmother's wand, Cinderella's
rags are magically turned into a glorious gown and off she goes to the Royal Ball.
But when the clock strikes midnight, the spell is
broken, leaving a single glass slipper...
the only key to the ultimate fairy-tale ending!
Cinderella (voice), played by Ilene Woods.
Lady Tremaine (voice), played by Eleanor Audley.
Fairy Godmother (voice), played by Verna Felton.
(credit only) (voice), played by Claire Du Brey.
Drizella (voice), played by Rhoda Williams.
Gus / Jaq (voice), played by James MacDonald.
Cinderella is a 1950 American animated musical fantasy film produced by
Walt Disney Productions and released by RKO Radio Pictures.
Based on Charles Perrault's 1697 fairy tale, the film follows Cinderella, the daughter of a widowed aristocrat, who is forced to become a servant of her
cruel stepmother and stepsisters, until Cinderella's fairy godmother grants her the chance to attend the royal ball and meet the prince.
The production was supervised by Ben Sharpsteen, and was directed by
Wilfred Jackson, Hamilton Luske, and Clyde Geronimi.
It features the voices of Ilene Woods, Eleanor Audley, Verna Felton, Rhoda
Williams, June Foray, James MacDonald, and Luis van Rooten.
During the early 1940s, Walt Disney Productions had suffered financially after losing
connections to the European film markets due to the outbreak of World War II.
Because of this, the studio endured commercial failures such as Pinocchio, Fantasia (both 1940) and Bambi (1942), all
of which would later become more successful with several re-releases in theaters and on home video.
By 1947, the studio was over $4 million in debt
and was on the verge of bankruptcy.
Walt Disney and his animators returned to feature film production in 1948 after producing a string of
package films with the idea of adapting Charles Perrault's Cendrillon into an animated film.
Cinderella was released to theatres on February 15, 1950.
It received critical acclaim and was a box office success, making it Disney's biggest hit since
Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937) and helping reverse the studio's fortunes.
It also received three Academy Award nominations, including Best Scoring of a Musical
Picture, Best Sound Recording, and Best Original Song for "Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo".
The film was followed by two direct-to-video sequels, Cinderella II: Dreams Come True (2002)
and Cinderella III: A Twist in Time (2007), and a live-action remake in 2015.
In 2018, Cinderella was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of princess, based on novel or
book, loss of loved one, mouse, ball.
The tone is emotional.